trustedid.com 2013-01-20

# TrustedID Privacy Policy

TrustedID® was founded with the mission of giving individuals control over their personal information and who has access to that information. Any information you provide to TrustedID will remain strictly confidential. Information provided to TrustedID will never be sold or put at risk of being compromised under any conditions! 

TrustedID has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at help@trustedid.com If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). 

**What is unique about TrustedID Privacy Policy?**  
TrustedID's privacy policy exceeds the industry standards required by congressional legislation. If you compare our policy to any of your financial institutions, you will clearly see that protecting your data is our number one priority. One requirement of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Financial Modernization Act of 1999, or GLB, requires financial institutions to provide customers with the ability to "opt-out" of information sharing. 

TrustedID knows you care about how your personal information is used and shared. We respect your privacy, and we are committed to protecting it. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. 

**This document includes information about:**

  1. Making the security of information a priority
  2. Collecting information
  3. Managing information
  4. Making sure information is accurate
  5. Honoring your preferences

**1\. Making the security of information a priority**

**TrustedID was built with the safety of your information as our biggest priority. We use the highest levels of security available on the Internet.**

While we cannot disclose the full details of our security procedures, we can share the following general steps that we take to protect you:

Any sensitive personally identifiable information entered into our website, such as your Social Security or credit card number, is safely transferred in an encrypted format using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. (To learn more about SSL, follow [this link](http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/S/SSL.html)). TrustedID employees with access to customer information undergo thorough background checks. Access to information is strictly limited. We use a variety of techniques to provide multiple layers of protection against network or physical intrusion. We constantly monitor our servers and physical location for unauthorized access. You will notice when you are on our website that some familiar indicators do appear in your browser to confirm the entire page is secure. These indicators include the small "lock" icon and the "s" in the Web address bar (for example, "https"). 

**2\. Collecting information**

**We collect only the information necessary to deliver the products and services you request.**

The information we gather from customers enables us to personalize and improve our services. We collect the following types of information from our customers. 

**Personal Information You Provide to Us:**

We may receive and store any information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then we may not be able to offer you our services, or you may not be able to take advantage of all of the features of our services. The Personal Information you provide may be used for such purposes as responding to your requests for certain products and services. The Personal Information that you provide to us under our terms and conditions will be used for the purposes described in those terms and conditions. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at help@trustedid.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Personal Information Collected Automatically:**

We may receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with our website or services. 

**Cookies:** Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we may transfer to your computer's hard drive through your browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages on our site are visited and by how many people. TrustedID cookies do not collect Personal Information, and we do not combine the general information collected through cookies with other Personal Information to tell us who you are or what your screen name or e-mail address is. Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. The use of cookies by our partners, or affiliates, is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. 

**Web Beacons:** We use a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information. 

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please contact us at help@trustedid.com. 

**Log Files:** TrustedID may choose to automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, computer MAC address, TrustedID cookie information, and the page you requested. Generally, our service may automatically collect usage information, such as the numbers and frequency of visitors to our site and its components, similar to TV ratings that indicate how many people watched a particular show. TrustedID only uses this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, and not in a manner that would identify you personally. This type of aggregate data enables us to figure out how often customers use parts of the website or services so that we can make the website appealing to as many customers as possible, and improve those services. 

**E-mail Communications:** We never ask customers to email us personal information. We may receive a confirmation when you open an e-mail from TrustedID if your computer supports this type of program. TrustedID may use this confirmation to help ensure the timeliness and effectiveness of correspondence. 

**Service-related Announcements:** We will send you strictly service-related announcements approximately every 90 days and on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. 

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account. 

**Registration:** In order to use this Website, you must first complete the registration form submitting your email address and creating a password. During registration you are required to give personal information including: name, mailing address, Date of Birth, Phone numbers, gender, Social Security Number and email address. We use this information to verify your identity as well as uniquely identify your information with credit bureaus and other data stores in order to secure it. 

You will receive emails during the registration process detailing steps you will need to follow for completion as well as important information you will want to retain for your records. 

TrustedID, Inc. is the sole owner of the information collected on TrustedID.com. 

**Public Forums:** Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at help@trustedid.com In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

**Orders:** If you purchase a product or service from us on our website order form, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date).  

We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you. 

**Social Security Numbers:** We require your social security number to enhance the protection offered by TrustedID. When you enter your social security number during our registration process, we encrypt it using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

**Supplementation of Personal Information:** To improve the security of our service, to protect your identity, and protect your information, we may verify your personal information by matching the information you provide to TrustedID against other publicly available information that we obtain from identification verification companies. This matching is done via secure systems and all your information, both that which you provide to TrustedID and that which we obtain through third parties, is held in strict confidence. 

**3\. Information Sharing**

Your privacy and the security of your data is our primary concern. Your trust is extremely important to us, and we will do everything in our power to live up to the trust you place in us. Personal Information about our customers is an important part of our business. We neither rent nor sell your Personal Information to anyone. We share Personal Information only with our business partners and affiliates as described below and as otherwise specifically described in the Terms and Conditions. 

Affiliated Businesses We Do Not Control: We are affiliated with a variety of businesses and work closely with them. In certain situations, these businesses may operate services at the TrustedID website or offer services or products to you through TrustedID's website. In other situations, TrustedID provides services, or offers products jointly with affiliated businesses. You may generally be able to recognize when an affiliated business is associated with your transaction when the TrustedID logo is not clearly in view. We may share information that is related to such transactions with that affiliated business, such as information regarding whether a customer's registration is completed, or whether a customer is an active member of the service. In the event you are a member of TrustedID's â€œIDSafe" service, TrustedID may share information with the third party that is providing you with the IDSafe membership (e.g. your employer), such as your name, address, date of registration and type of membership. 

Agents: We may employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf such as an email provider to send specific types of emails, or payment processor to process your credit card and need to share information (Name, Address, Phone Number, Email Address) with them to provide products or services to you. Unless we tell you differently, TrustedID's agents do not have any right to use Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. You hereby consent to our sharing of Personal Information for the above purposes. 

Promotional Offers: We will never send offers to customers on behalf of other businesses. 

Business Transfers: In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if TrustedID, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, customer information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of TrustedID may continue to use your Personal Information as set forth in this policy. You will be notified via a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

Protection of TrustedID and Others: We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Website, enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of TrustedID, our employees, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

With Your Consent: Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be able to prevent the sharing of this information. 

**Is personal information about me secure?**

Your TrustedID account Personal Information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. 

You need to ensure unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can contact us via the contact us section of our website. 

**4\. Making sure information is accurate**

Keeping your information accurate is very important. TrustedID may allow you to access you Personal Information for the purpose of viewing, and in certain situations, updating that information. The types of information that you can access update will change as our website changes. This can be seen when you log into the customer portal with your email address and password and choosing "update". 

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or deactivate it by making the logging into the customer portal using your email address and password and going to the UPDATE page or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. 

**5\. Honoring your preferences**

As stated previously, you can always opt not to disclose information to TrustedID, even though it may be needed to receive services or take advantage of certain TrustedID website and product features. You may be able to add or update certain information on pages, such as those that may be listed in the "What Personal Information Can I Access" section above. When you update information, however, we may maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. You may request deletion of your TrustedID account by notifying us using our contact form on the website and responding affirmatively to any confirmation we may send. Please note that some information may remain in our records after deletion of your account. You may limit the amount of email you receive from us by de-selecting "email" as a preference for alert notification from within the customer portal. As explained earlier, the majority of browsers allow you to monitor and restrict our use of cookies. Please note, however, that if your browser does not accept cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of some of our services or website features. 

**Third Party Web Sites and Services**

This Privacy Policy applies only to the TrustedID website and service. This site may contain links or referrals to other web sites and services not operated or controlled by TrustedID (the .Third Party Services.). The policies and procedures that are described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to the Third Party Services, and any links or referrals from TrustedID do not imply that TrustedID endorses or has reviewed the Third Party Services. We suggest contacting those Third Party Services directly for information on their privacy policies and practices. 

**Changes to this privacy policy**

TrustedID may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected. If we make material changes in the way we use Personal Information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on our Website prior to the changes taking effect. 

**Questions or concerns**

If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us at 1.888.548.7878. 

TrustedID, Inc.  
395 Page Mill Road  
Suite 130  
Palo Alto, CA 94306
